fanhistory.com 2009-03-21

# Fanhistory.com:Privacy policy - Fan History Wiki

### From Fan History Wiki

 |  Policy   
This article defines official Fan History policy.   
---|---  
  
## Contents

[hide]

  * 1 Summary
  * 2 Publishing on the wiki and public data
    * 2.1 Identification of an author
      * 2.1.1 IP addresses
    * 2.2 E-mail
    * 2.3 Cookies
    * 2.4 Passwords
  * 3 Private logging
    * 3.1 Policy on release of data derived from page logs
  * 4 Sharing information with third parties
  * 5 Security of information
  * 6 User data
    * 6.1 Removal of user accounts
  * 7 Deletion of content
  * 8 Links to other sites
  * 9 Notification of changes

## [edit] Summary 

If you only read the Fan History wiki site, no more information is collected than is typically collected in server logs by web sites in general. 

To contribute to the wiki, you may desire to log in, and by contributing, you are **publishing** every word you post publicly. If you write something, assume that it will be retained forever. This includes articles, user pages, and talk pages. Some limited exceptions are described below. 

## [edit] Publishing on the wiki and public data 

Simply _visiting_ the web site does not expose your identity publicly . When you _edit_ any page in the wiki, **you are publishing a document**. This is a public act, and you are identified publicly by username or IP address with that edit as its author. 

### [edit] Identification of an author 

To publish a page in the wiki, you may choose to log in. If you are logged in, you are identified by your username. You can use your real name, though in interests of privacy Fan History suggests using a pseudonym. Do _not_ use your e-mail address as a username. Whatever username you selected when you created your account will be seen on the main page when you are logged in, and will be attached to any edits you may make. 

Remember to log out or disconnect yourself after each session if logged in on a shared computer to prevent others from using your identity. 

#### [edit] IP addresses

When logged in under your username, your IP address cannot be seen by other visitors to the wiki; even administrators cannot see your IP address without being granted special permissions. Your IP address, and its connection to any usernames that share it, is not available to the general public, but may be released under certain circumstances (see below). 

If you choose not to log in when publishing in the wiki, your IP address will be identified with any edits you may make. It will be treated as public information, and will be visible to anyone visiting the wiki. In addition, Fan History will consider such use as a tacit agreement on your part that your IP address can be treated as pubic information. 

In all cases, the IP addresses you publish from will be stored on the wiki servers and can be viewed by [certain privileged users](http://fanhistory.com/w/index.php?title=Special%3AListusers&username=&group=checkuser&limit=50 "http://fanhistory.com/w/index.php?title=Special%3AListusers&username=&group=checkuser&limit=50"). 

### [edit] E-mail

When you register to use Fan History, you are prompted for an optional e-mail address. You do not have to provide an e-mail address; however, it is helpful for several reasons if you do: 

  * To receive e-mail from other logged-in users who click "E-mail this user" on your user page. 
  * To receive e-mail notification of pages of interest in your watchlist through configuration of your preferences. 
  * To reset your password if you forget it. 

Your address will not be revealed to users who send you e-mail unless you respond, though there is the possibility of an accidental revealing if the e-mail bounces. The e-mail address may be used by Fan History to communicate with users on a wider scale; specifically, about the wiki site. 

You can remove your e-mail address from your preferences at any time to prevent it from being used. 

### [edit] Cookies 

Cookies are set by visiting the wiki as Fan History utilizes both third party tools (such as advertisements) and analytic tools (such as quantcast). 

Cookies may also be set when you log in, so you can avoid typing in your user name (or, optionally, your password) on your next visit. 

### [edit] Passwords 

All users are encouraged to select strong passwords and never to share them. No one at Fan History shall knowingly expose the password of another user to the public, either directly or indirectly; doing so merits disciplinary action. No Fan History administrator will ever ask a user for their password. 

## [edit] Private logging 

Every time you visit a web page, you send a lot of information to the web server. Most web servers routinely maintain access logs with a portion of this information, which can be used to get an overall picture of what pages are popular, what other sites link to this one, and what web browsers people are using. It is not the intention of Fan History to use this information to keep track of individually identifiable users. 

Here's a sample of what's logged for one page view: 

    64.164.82.142 - - [21/Oct/2003:02:03:19 +0000]
    "GET /mediawiki/index.php HTTP/1.1" 200 18084
    "<http://fanhistory.com/wikiwiki/index.php/Main_Page>"
    "Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; U; PPC Mac OS X; en-us) AppleWebKit/85.7 (KHTML, like Gecko) Safari/85.5"

Log data may be examined by developers in the course of solving technical problems. IP addresses of users, derived either from those logs or from records in the database, may be used to correlate usernames and network addresses of edits in investigating abuse of the wiki, including vandalism, harassment of other users, or disruption of the wiki. 

### [edit] Policy on release of data derived from page logs 

Personally identifiable data collected in the server logs or through records in the database may be released by those with access in the following situations: 

  * In response to a valid subpoena or other compulsory request from law enforcement. 
  * With permission of the affected user. 
  * Where the information pertains to page views generated by a spider or bot and its dissemination is necessary to illustrate or resolve technical issues. 
  * Where the user has been vandalizing articles or persistently behaving in a disruptive way, data may be released to assist in the targeting of IP blocks, or to assist in the formulation of a complaint to relevant Internet Service Providers. 
  * Where it is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, or safety of Fan History, its users, or the public. 

Fan History policy does not permit public distribution of such information under any other circumstances. 

## [edit] Sharing information with third parties 

Fan History reserves the right to share information with third parties regarding usage statistics from the wiki. This information includes, but is not limited to, information gathered by analytic tools (such as Google Analytics, Quantcast, ljToys, and StatCounter), server logs, and reports generated from server logs. E-mail addresses will not be shared or sold unless the site for which they were provided is sold in its entirety. Fan History may publicly present aggregate data that contains no personally identifiable information. 

In the event that Fan History or one of its sites is sold, registered users with a confirmed e-mail address will be notified in advance by e-mail unless the new owner agrees to honor this privacy policy. 

## [edit] Security of information

Fan History takes data security seriously, and only its owner (Laura) and technician (Emufarmers) have direct access to private data. However, there is always the remote possibility that an attacker could gain access to the server: Fan History cannot guarantee against unauthorized access to any information you provide. 

## [edit] User data 

Data on users, such as the times at which they edited and the number of edits they have made, are publicly available via "user contributions" lists, and possibly in aggregated forms published by other users. 

### [edit] Removal of user accounts 

Once created, user accounts will not be removed, although they may be disabled by request or in cases of abuse. Users may request that their usernames be changed, but Fan History does not guarantee that a name will be changed on request. 

## [edit] Deletion of content 

Removing text from wiki pages does not permanently delete it. In normal articles, anyone can look at a previous version and see what was there. If an article is truly _deleted,_ any user with administrator access on the wiki can see what was deleted. Information can be permanently deleted by those people with access to the servers, but there is no guarantee this will happen except in response to legal action. 

## [edit] Links to other sites

This wiki site makes it simple for anyone to add links to other sites. Fan History is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site, and to read the privacy statements of every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This includes sites that we might make active use of at various times. 

## [edit] Notification of changes

This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Fan History. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes here and update the news section on Fan History's main page so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances (if any) we disclose it. If we ever decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify registered users with confirmed e-mail addresses in advance via e-mail. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
